James Schreiber

James.Schreiber93@gmail.com

ischrbr.github.io/portfolio/

Mobile: +61 408 767 485



linkedin.com/in/techsmechs

Summary

A Mechanical Engineer with 3 years experience of Process Engineering in the Aerospace/Defence Industry. I am a problem solver, driven by understanding the "in's and out's" of a process, across all disciplines, then applying the lessons to new projects.

My focus on cross-disciplinary skills allows me to, autonomously, deliver comprehensive solutions. More importantly, these skills enable me to strategise a project, and select the appropriate tools to minimize efforts during development. I.e (Rule 1: Pick the right tool for the job).

My experience over recent years is primarily in creating and maintaining production documentation, as well as hands on assembly and R&D. During which, I have been able to utilise Python, JavaScript and C++ to resolve challenges in an efficient manner. My hobbies have always added value to my work. I can often be found learning or practicing new topics, keeping current on new technologies, and thinking of new ways to challenge myself.

I am a strong addition to any development team, with a wide variety of skills and knowledge perfect for cross-disciplinary projects, and always learning, recently earning a Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate with Monash University, as well as Google's Professional Certificate in IT Automation with Python.

Every job can be broken into constraints, derived from goals and requirements. I constantly refer back to these constraints when making informed decisions, and try to be a catalyst for that way of thinking in a team.

Skills

CAD C/C++ SOL

Troubleshooting Python Mongo

Mechatronic Assembly HTML React

Process Design CSS Angular

Technical Writing JavaScript Redux

Tool Design Node **TypeScript**

IoT applications Deployment GraphQL

Projects

Trakka TLX Searchlight New Product Introduction | whitepaper

URL: https://trakkasystems.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/TRK3837-TLX-Brochure-screen.pdf

Brought a new aerospace product from R&D to Production.

Leading the implementation of a flagship product from prototype to standard production within aerospace standards, within one year.

- Tested, developed and documented the assembly process
- Trained employee on technically advanced topics and procedures.
- Designed and implemented processes to maintain traceability of required testing and measurements through Production.

Roboteam Customer Support for the NZDF | website

URL: https://robo-team.com/

Providing technical support for a project with the NZDF EOD squadron.

- Learned to disassemble, maintain and reassemble several products and variants of advanced mechatronic systems within two months.
- Trained operators on basic maintenance and safe operation.

Twitter clone | Firebase, React.js, Redux and Material-UI | demo

URL: https://oopini.web.app/

Twitter clone built from a tutorial but refactored for async/await. (Code available on request).

- Utilizes firebase authentication, functions, database and hosting.
- User, Post and Error data is dispatched through Redux.
- Material-UI used for styling. Server validated errors are handled with styling..

Second-opinion | ML5.js, P5.js and MaterializeCSS | git | demo

URL: https://github.com/jschrbr/second-opinion

A simple machine learning web application where the user can train a custom model based on visual likes and dislikes.

- Utilizes ML5.js to create custom like/dislike classifiers extracted from the MobileNet model.
- DOM manipulation through P5.js
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

employ-EE | Node and MySQL | git

URL: https://github.com/jschrbr/employe-EE

A node base CLI application for keeping track of employees and role/department specific information.

- Utilizes ML5.js to create custom like/dislike classifiers extracted from the MobileNet model.
- DOM manipulation through P5.js
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

Simple-bin | MaterializeCSS, HTML, Javascript | git | demo

URL: https://github.com/jschrbr/simple-bin

Just a really simple dec. to bin. Calculator web app. Material styling using MaterializeCSS.

- Nice looking calculator, styled to intuit the user on how binary to decimal conversions work.
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

Work Experience

Trakka Tech - Technical Support Consultant

April 2020-Present, Melbourne.

- Managing support for system issues.
- Conducting yearly maintenance tasks.

Trakka Systems - Process Improvement Manager and Production Engineer

Feb 2019 - Feb 2020, Melbourne

- Successfully implemented a new flagship product into an regulated production environment.
 - Achieved by implementing electronic work instructions to efficiently disseminate technical information, while easily managing updates and distribution.
 - Authored hundreds of guides and work instructions using Dozuki software.
 - Created web apps to interface with Dozuki's API and create reports using existing or improved templates.
- Onboarded dozens of staff in highly demanding technical roles.

Trakka Systems - Process Engineer

Feb 2017 - Feb 2019, Melbourne

- Managed Production environment handling non-conformances and other issues that could affect on time delivery.
 - Maintaining existing documentation using Microsoft Office tools
 - Utilising existing SharePoint tools for managing non-conformances and issues
 - Creating Work Instructions and other technical documents based on requirements specified on sharepoint
 - Created python scripts for analysing Navision data that was not available natively.
 - Implemented changes in existing documentation under a AS9100 certified Quality
 Management System using the Plan-Do-Check-Act lifecycle.
- Plentiful experience in hands-on assembly in Production and R&D environments.

Kevin Stahlmon - Apprentice

Aug 2014 - Dec 2016, Byron Bay

- Learned the basics of working with hand and power tools.
- Initial exposure to larger scale cross disciplinary projects.

Starseed Gardens - Technical Officer

Feb 2013 - Dec 2016, Byron Bay

• An opportunity to learn and expose myself to a variety of fields including agriculture, mechanical, electrical, plumbing and IT.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

Monash University, Victoria (2020)

Bachelors of Mechanical Engineering

Griffith University, Gold Coast (2013-2017)

VCE

Bialik College, Victoria (2010-2011)

Certifications/Licenses

Google's Professional Certificate in IT Automation with Python - (2020)

Certified IPC Specialists under IPC-620 C - (re-certified 2019)